hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah grakowski and on this podcast I
walk you through how to grow in your
life and in your business if you're a
coach trainer or mentor and you want to
make more money in your business you're
in the right spot that's the new year
and I got a new message for you I'm so
excited to share this with you you know
one of the biggest things that we can
get caught up in is
in the grind of building our business
and doing all the things and planning
and strategizing and doing all the
Practical aspects of it is we lose sight
of our vision
and our belief do you have vision and
belief
in what you're doing in your business
when's the last time that you said I
believe that I can do it even if
your current reality it seems impossible
even if
in the middle of your circumstance
seems like it's never going to happen
you know what you create in your life
you create in your business
comes out of
what you actually believe is possible
and so
if you're struggling and you're saying
well I need to make money I need to make
money
but but you don't see a light at the end
of the tunnel
that becomes a hindrance to you from
being able to successfully build a
coaching business
no and you'll end up striving and
and spinning your wheels and struggling
to do the work
because you're so focused on the
everyday you're so focused on the
minutia
you're so focused on what to do I have
to do rather than going big picture and
having a vision your vision is what's
actually going to drive the actions
because you're going to have that Vision
written down and that's why people do
vision boards as well when's the last
time that you made some goals when's the
last time that you looked at and said
Okay I want my life to be like this six
months from now
I want my life to be like this three
I do that constantly and and every three
to six months I adjust and I change
what I'm actually
having a goal for I I tweak and I change
what my vision is because
things start to move in different
directions they start to Pivot
what are areas that I want to grow in in
my personal life
and then what happens is when you have a
vision for the life that you're creating
see not just a vision of how much money
you're going to make
but I want you to have a vision
for the life that you're going to
experience
your everyday life that you're gonna
experience I got a new baby on the way
and my life is going to be changing
I've been having vision
for how that life is going to look how
I'm going to build my business how I'm
going to do everyday things
might look different than how I've done
them I'm not going to spend as much time
perfecting everything
because truly having a child I don't
have time to I don't have the energy the
the extra Expendable energy to make
things perfect
because I'm taking care of my son
I'm taking care of my wife I'm taking
care of my family I'm taking care of my
clients
and so that's one of the biggest things
is that when we have a vision
it helps us narrow in on what's
essential
what's important
what actually is truly matters
in the grand scheme of things what
actually
truly moves the needle forward
it's actually a lot less than most
people think it is a lot of people think
they need to do all this stuff
when really there's like one or two
little things that you do that make all
the difference in your life
but many times
those one to two little things were
avoiding because it's painful
or because we're afraid of it not going
a certain way
or we don't think that it's good enough
and so that's why again returning back
to what is your vision
what is the vision that you have
for the life that you're creating
sitting with that vision
not so that you get disappointed
that you're not living it right now see
that becomes the temptation
is we end up having vision and then we
may be are disappointed that it's not
the current life that we live that the
current reality that we're walking in
doesn't look like that Vision that we
had
and this becomes
disappointing
and we end up fighting and striving and
working harder to make the thing happen
or we end up getting stuck because we
don't know what path to take we don't
know what to do returning back to your
vision
is actually going to be one of the best
things that you can do some of you
might not have had Vision in a long time
because when you did you got so
disappointed that it didn't go that way
that you actually subconsciously made a
decision I'm never gonna have Vision
again
I'm never going to dream for the future
again because I don't want to be
disappointed again I don't want it to go
how it did last time
and we end up making these choices
and decisions
for our life These long-term big picture
choices that are not going to help us
that aren't going to move us forward
because we don't want to be disappointed
truth is life isn't always going to go
how you envision it but that's no reason
to not have vision
like your vision is just a direction to
kind of aim the needle but without
Direction you'll be spinning in circles
nowhere to go
have no no guidance no Direction you'll
just be flip-flopping everywhere
struggling
to experience the life that you want
and so I just I want to challenge you
today
to get a vision
to start dreaming for what is the life
that you want to live
what is the life that you want to design
if you knew you couldn't fail what would
you do
what would you design what would you
change
and then I want to ask you why is your
life not like that right now and this
isn't to get guilty this isn't for you
to feel upset
or disappointed
it's for you to identify okay what moves
do I need to make now
to start to make that happen
because once we have a vision we work
backwards from that vision and we say
okay what do I need to do in my life to
make that a reality
maybe you need to start writing your
offer copy use chat GPT or Jasper to map
out your your course
maybe you need to
start building your funnel start growing
your email list
run a virtual event
get some people in front of you that you
can sell your coaching program to
but what's the biggest thing that you're
putting off
that's stopping you from going after
that vision
and write it down
and start to get really curious
in your everyday life
starts to get really curious
in your daily life
as to
what is standing in the way of you and
that Vision that you have
you can move any of those things you can
change any of those things a lot of
people give me these excuses of well I
can't get rid of my kids so now I can't
build my vision
first off that's called an extreme and
that's being really attached to throwing
up your hands and saying nothing's ever
going to work out for me it's always
going to be this way your kids are a
blessing first off and they should be a
reason
to motivate you to actually make more
money to motivate you to build a
business not as an excuse or a reason
why you can't
so often we end up looking at our life
situation saying if only things were
different than they really are
then I'd be successful
and that's a big lie
because people with
harder situations than you
accomplish so much
this isn't for you to be critical or
beat yourself up over
but it's a reality check
any one of you can create
the life you want
you can imagine anything you can imagine
can come true for you
now you might need help a community like
our coaching Community like our client
growth accelerator community
a mentor like me you can ask me
questions if you get stuck
along the way about your situation that
you're going through you might need to
work with a therapist to heal
those herding areas inside of you
that disappointment
if we're so attached to how we wish
things should be how we think things
should have gone
will miss the opportunities that are
right in front of us to make the best
with what we got
and that's what you got to do is you got
to make the best with what you got
instead of trying to
Force exactly how you see it in your
brain see having a vision isn't about
you now forcing it to happen the biggest
reason why we avoid
making a vision while we avoid believing
that we could do great things is because
we don't want to get disappointed
because we don't want to get let down
and so that's why when you set your
intention
when you create a vision
when you
see
how you want your life to be but then
you do so with an open hand
detached
you let go of needing the outcome to go
how you perfectly see it I'll tell you
this
it's never going to go exactly perfectly
how you see it it's just not
and so let's actually lay down
that facade
that if things don't go perfectly my way
then they're wrong
and realize that maybe how they did go
was setting you up for something better
and then our vision changes and it
morphs and it evolves and we end up
growing with our vision over time and it
turns more into
what it really is supposed to be
this one thing right here
will radically change your life
is when you start
seeing yourself
successful and you start believing
that Financial wealth and prosperity are
possible for you that you start
believing that you're going to have a
growing business or whatever that vision
is that you have that's your that your
family is going to be taking care of
that your life is going to be peaceful
and stress-free but we start imagining
this vision
I talk to people so often they they they
struggle
to imagine anything
to have any imagination for just what's
beyond right in front of them because
they've been beaten down by life so much
because they've been hurt by life so
much
if that's the case again I feel for you
let's not ever lose sight of vision
let's not ever
become so attached to One Vision that we
get upset
that our happiness is only tied to
things going our way and we actually
learn to let go and surrender the
outcome and what I say I surrender the
outcome to God
I Surrender the outcome to Holy Spirit
and I say God
if you got a better plan show me
show me that better plan I want the best
that you have for me
not and what I might imagine might not
be the best
and so
I'll say Lord I want the best that you
have for me not
not that God is gonna
give me anything crappy because he's not
God doesn't give us crappy stuff
he doesn't
some of y'all you might have teaching or
theology that you've been taught
that God gives us crappy stuff to teach
us lessons that God does crappy things
in our life
but really
when it's something that we don't like
when it's when it when there's no joy in
it
it's actually because we're so attached
to what we want that we're not accepting
and saying wow everything that God gives
me is good
everything that God has presented and
brings into my life is for
incredible things to happen
that every single gift of God is a good
thing
and we start walking in that and listen
I get it
we lose loved ones
how could we find joy in that right
how can we find joy in our grief and our
sorrow
that's there's pain in the world
there's hard stuff that happens there's
terrible stuff that happens to people
but we can't lose sight of our vision we
can't let those things that happen to us
now decide well because this happened
now I can't move forward in my vision
because this happened now I can't
step into
what God has for me
see that's a choice that we end up
making ourselves that because this
situation happened
now
my life is ruined
everything in my life is terrible and
listen we need to grieve I'm not I'm not
knocking grief at all
I want you to grieve it's important to
grieve
grief doesn't have a timeline either
grief doesn't have a time limit
you need to allow yourself to feel that
pain it's okay it's okay to
and then realize
that you're here in the present moment
still able to create your dreams even if
they might not look exactly how you
imagined
even if they might not look exactly how
you wanted
sometimes we need to grieve the death of
our dreams
sometimes we need to grieve
things that didn't go our way
sometimes we need to have grief for okay
I thought something was going to go this
way and then it didn't
and so now what better thing is coming
down the pipeline for me you know when I
used to work with my mom I have to
grieve the vision of how I thought my
life was going to go by working with her
when I started my own business
I actually went Kicking and Screaming
starting my own business because I
really always thought that I was only
going to do it with my mom and I was so
attached to that
and truthfully it was the best thing
that ever happened to me but it was hard
it was painful I thought my life was
over it felt like it was over
how I had imagined things to go I was
making a almost a half a million dollar
a year income that went to zero
no longer working with my mom
and yeah it was the best thing that
happened
and my wife and I now
you know we've made more in the last
five months that we were in
in two years of working with my mom in
our own business
and so it all started with
what I'm telling you right now
it all started with
having a vision
seeing something sitting with the vision
changing the vision that's the one of
the most important things is is be
willing to change the vision
if God's got a better plan
be willing to adjust it be willing to
tweak it
we end up being so caught up in how we
think things should go
when there's literally like
something better we end up we end up
striving for pennies when God has
billions
in store for us
and yet we end up being so attached to
well I wanted my pennies because I
imagined that I would have these pennies
and and and truthfully like God will let
us just stick with our pennies
he will
until we say you know what I Surrender
I let go I detach from what I what I
want
but Lord give me a vision give me a
direction to head in direct my footsteps
direct where I'm going
to direct where I'm walking
and I trust
that it will all work out for good
when you walk in that when you walk in
accepting
that things will all work out for good
for you
when you start accepting
that things will go well for you
and things will be
absolutely incredible and listen
it does like like I'm not I'm not being
weird here it doesn't always go well for
us
you're on planet Earth right
I'm on planet Earth things don't always
go
perfect
they're not supposed to
but that's not a reason to not have
vision and Hope
and when you have the most hope
it allows you to to
design your life it allows you to build
and create
whatever you and God you're partnering
with heaven
to build
you're partnering with
a bigger plan and a bigger vision
than just what you can imagine
but start to sit with start to write
down start to have a vision start to
imagine the life that you want
with an open hand
being detached
but then say okay now what do I need to
do
to start to bring that to pass
trust me
it'll be revealed what you need to do
It's usually the scariest thing that you
know you need to do that you need to do
It's usually the hardest thing
that you know you need to do
that you need to do
but it's worth it
in the end
we gotta stop trying to
look for comfort in our life we gotta
stop trying to look for
and I'm not talking about striving
self-care is so important taking care of
yourself is important resting is
literally
the fuel of success rest is the fuel of
success
but we don't want to get stuck
to where we're not doing anything
because we're just
just in limbo
and we feel like we have no direction we
feel like we have nowhere where we're
going and that's too often where people
get because things didn't go their way
or they got hurt or a trauma happened or
or something
a transition in their life
working through transition
still building still walking out the
direction I got a new baby on the way
but I'm still walking out the direction
and the vision
that grows my business
because I know that that's the right
path for right now in this season
and so for you I want you to think about
that what's one to two things that maybe
you know that you need to do
to turn your vision into a reality
your vision is not going to become a
reality just by you sitting on the couch
doing nothing
it's gonna become a reality by you
actually walking it out
by you actually
putting one foot in front of the other
by you actually taking steps
to see it start to come to pass
what's one to two steps that you need to
do today
this week that you've been putting off
to start to see results listen
to you that next step for you to take is
going to be joining my coaching program
joining my client growth accelerator
if the doors aren't open right now you
can get on the waiting list if I go into
my website
join the waiting list when we open the
doors back up again we'd love to have
you in there to help you if you're a
coach if you're a mentor if you're a
trainer to start to get more of those
clients
Join one of the free events one of the
free trainings that we do
we do them every single month
to help you
grow your business get more clients
build the nuances build the foundations
that actually create Financial results
and so if that's you again this podcast
is a great resource
having a mentor like me in your corner
to help guide you and direct you along
the way is invaluable
to you walking out the vision that you
have for your life
grow your life everybody we'll talk soon
have a good one
[Applause]